Have you ever felt you were going to die?
I don't remember how long ago
it was, but there was one time.
It was during a fight with the last general
of the Dark Knights, or the one before.
Didn't think I'd make it out of that one.
You did, though.
Eventually you brought
his head back to me.
You felt it then, never again?
Hmm.
If I did, I don't remember.
Why are you asking?
I tell someone like you worries
about dying, am I right?
Not true, my dear Bercouli.
I feel death hovering
over me every single day.
It is there in my dreams and
in the morning when I awaken.
Why?
Because I still do not control everything.
Because I still have enemies who live.
And because the longer I live, it is
possible that at some point in the future,
there will come a new enemy.
Point taken, my lady.
I guess being the Pontifex
ain't easy after all, huh?
Your Eminence?
I didn't get what you
meant then, but I do now.
I want you more!
I want you more! I want you more!
I want
you more!
Now I can't even know how to pass.
Because today, I will turn it to theكرer!
And I will tell you how to use it.
I will be beasts of the world.
My dream is one of the best events.
I will get you back the question.
This question is if you don't know.
It's not a perfect moment.
I will be able to do it!
It doesn't matter.
I will not know.
I will be the world.
I will never know.
More than one thing.
Just one thing
Here, eat up.
I have to say, you're looking much
healthier this morning, Kirito.
And your appetite's back with a vengeance.
Perhaps spending the night with
four lovely ladies is the reason.
I'll be damned.
It looks like Emperor Vecta's
got some bold strategies in mind.
He's taking a risk, and
it's gonna cost him big.
This is war, folks.
I want to remind you, this
ain't the time for mercy.
The enemy's making their way
across that canyon Asuna made.
This is our chance to stop them. Chance?
Yeah.
Keep going. Hurry!
I want you to cast some ropes over to the
other side, and send your people across.
If they fall, they fall.
Execute anyone who doesn't comply.
What the hell?
The five tribes should be
conquering the human empire,
not chasing after some priestess of light.
We're out here dying for nothing!
Come on come on move it get across all
you can hurry before the enemy notices
Look out!
The Integrity Knights are coming!
Protect the ropes till
the rest of us get across!
Stop it!
This...
This ain't no war.
They can't even defend themselves.
My people trained for this, to shimmy
across a rope and die for no reason at all.
Forgive me.
No doubt about it,
the Human Empire's A .I .s are slightly
superior to the Dark Territories.
Well done.
As far as adaptability goes,
they're on a whole other level.
You're up, Critter.
Don't blow it.
And for my next trick sinking the
underworld's time to the real world?
What no way is this for real?
Are they crazy?
A pvp with lifelike human avatars?
And realistic violence?
Do you mean we can like cut
off arms and heads and stuff?
No way!
No restrictions!
Hell to the yes!
This developer's adventurous!
Yeah baby!
I'm so signing up for this! Beta!
Don't push!
There's enough Dark Knight
accounts for everyone!
Go forth, my dudes and The
chocolate human army to ribbons.
Daddy! Mommy!
I have to do something. But what?
Xenon, it's Yui!
Yui?
What are you doing?
I'm sorry to call so late,
but it's an emergency.
Get dressed.
There's a taxi waiting out front.
I sent the address in the
fastest route to your phone.
Make sure to follow it.
What's going on?
Where am I going?
Daddy and Mommy are in danger.
I'll explain on the way.
Driver, take me to Minato
Ward in Tokyo, please.
Sorry I left without telling you, Mom.
But Kazuto's in trouble and he needs me.
It's been ten hours since Asuna
logged into the underworld.
So in there, it's been a year.
What's taking her so long?
The world's end alter can't
be that far away from her.
Or can it?
Hey, Keeks! The phone!
Kikuoka and Subcon,
talk to me. Hello, sir.
I know I'm not supposed to
call HQ unless it's important.
This is Hiroki at Wrath Roppongi.
We've got an issue here.
I think it's some kind of prank.
A couple visitors just showed up at
our location without an appointment.
Visitors?
Who are they? Clients?
No, they're definitely not clients,
but they seem to know a lot about us.
They're girls.
Two teenage girls.
What?
Teenagers, you said?
Yeah.
Anyway, they knew your name and that
you were at Wrath HQ, so I let them in.
They said I should call you and ask you
to check the FLA rate of the Underworld.
They said it was urgent.
Holy!
It's one-to-one? Since when?
Hey, Hiroki, did the girls
tell you their names?
Yes, sir, but the names they
gave are obviously fake.
They said not to worry,
you'd know who they were.
Hold on, I wrote them down.
Let's see, one called herself
Sinon, and the other Leafa.
It sounds crazy, but that's
what they told me to tell you.
I swear, he's in a coma and he still
managed to get caught up in something crazy.
I mean, a full-on AI called Alice who was
born in a virtual world made by the SDF?
This is way beyond VR games
and there's no going back.
Poor Alice.
She's so special and they just
want her to fly fighter jets.
Ultimately, yes, but
they won't right away.
Wrath will probably use her to demonstrate
the technology to the world first.
The hijackers aboard the Ocean Turtle,
however, aren't interested in demonstrations.
I think once they get her, they'll
use her for what she was intended.
Know anything else about those creeps?
Like who they are or where they're from?
I can't confirm it.
But I think they're U .S.
military or intelligence.
What?
They're behind it?
Oh my god.
Again, I can't confirm
they're involved with this.
But if they are, and Alice
does fall into their hands,
they'll use her for drone warfare.
I know Daddy and Mommy wouldn't
want that to happen to her.
Because Alice…
Alice is proof!
Her existence proves all VR
worlds starting with SAO are real,
that those who lived
in them had real lives.
She's the result of massive
amounts of the time,
energy, and imagination
of thousands of humans.
I'm convinced.
Beyond a doubt, she's why
the seed package was created.
Its true purpose, to give
birth to someone like her.
Throughout all the connected worlds
that sprang up from the seed,
so many people have laughed, cried,
suffered, and loved.
It was the radiance of all those
souls shimmering with life that made
it possible for a new form of
humanity to be born in the underworld.
Daddy and Mommy, Leafa, Klein,
Lisbeth, Silica, Egil, and Sinon.
It's the combination of your
hearts and so many others,
all woven together in a big
tapestry that gave birth to Alice.
Yeah, you're right.
It's all connected.
People.
And time.
And our hearts, too.
Flowing like a big river.
It's okay, Iui.
Don't cry.
We'll rescue Kirito and Asuna.
I promise.
We'll do whatever it takes
to get them out of this.
You can count on that.
Damn straight.
You should have come to us sooner.
If there's a chance to get them
out, hell, we're taking it.
You got that right.
I owe him as much as anyone.
About damn time I started paying him back.
You guys, thank you so much.
Seriously, thank you.
Now the hard part.
There's 30,000 American VR MMO players
diving, and soon it could go up to 100 thou.
The Human Army's just a
bunch of targets to them.
What's stopping us from
doing what the hijackers did?
We can post on the same
US VR MMO sites, too.
We'll tell the players about the
experiment and the fake beta.
I'm pretty sure they'll listen.
At the center of it
all is the struggle for
military secrets between
Japan and America.
If we told anyone about that,
it would just make this worse.
If we said they'd be killing real
people, not avatars, maybe...
Oh, who am I kidding?
Well,
I say we tear a page out of their playbook
We'll post a notice for
the beta test ourselves
Then we get the RAF guys
to hand out accounts
And I bet we could get 30
or 40,000 logged on easy
That's a great idea, man, but there's one
problem You gonna tell me what that is?
The time
Here in Japan, it's 4.30 in the morning
Besides us, there's not a
whole lot of folks online.
But in Los Angeles, it's
half past noon right now!
In 3.30 in New York, the U .S.
has way more active players online.
Aikil is correct about that.
We couldn't get the number
of players we need right now.
It would be way less than 10,000.
Our accounts would be the same level as
the Americans, so we'd be evenly matched.
Fighting all of them
off would be impossible.
But, like, maybe Wrath has more god
accounts like the one Asuna's using.
We can't start from scratch.
We need as much time as
Kirito to level up enough.
Crap, game over then. No.
There are strong accounts, both in
terms of level and in equipment.
The Americans' default
accounts can't compare.
Really?
How do we get them?
That's the best part.
The accounts are already yours.
They're the ones you're
logged in with now.
Huh?
You must convert them.
If you do,
then you and all the other
VR MMO players you recruit
will start with stronger
accounts than the Americans.
You're all leveled up already.
Just convert and log in. Of course.
Why didn't any of us think of that?
Although, I should mention,
this plan involves some risk.
What I'm about to tell you
is not some kind of prank.
There's a place called the Underworld.
It's a virtual world based on the
seed, made by Japanese researchers.
As I stand here, tens of thousands of
American players are logging into it.
They've been told it's a beta
for a hack and slash game,
and they can kill anyone they come across.
But the people of the Underworld are real.
They're not just NPCs.
They're true bottom-up AIs, with
feelings and souls, like us.
We need your help to protect them,
but there's no time to level up there.
But if you convert your character
accounts to the Underworld,
we can save their people!
I know you well, and I
trust your intentions.
You wouldn't have called us so early
just so you could play a trick on us.
And the fact Kirito hasn't
logged on for over ten
days suggests whatever is
going on is indeed serious.
But A .I.'s with human souls?
And the U .S.
military out to steal them?
It all seems so far-fetched.
Diving in would be the
only way to confirm it.
In private,
you told me you had other concerns, that
converting our accounts would have risks.
You should explain what
those are before we decide.
Sure.
Here's what I know.
The Underworld isn't a VR MMO game.
It's a simulated civilization,
so you'll be faced with a
few issues once you dive in.
The first one is, there's no user
interface to call up and manipulate.
Once you're logged in, you
can't log yourself out.
The only way for you to log
out is by dying in there.
That brings me to another issue
you all need to know about.
The underworld doesn't have a pain
absorber function if you take enough
damage to drop your HP to zero you'll
experience loads of virtual pain and
finally the underworld's
in a chaotic state right
now and the devs can't
fully operate it so once you
convert your character data
to the underworld there's
There's no guarantee you'll
be able to convert it back.
And worse, if you die there,
there's a good chance you might
lose your character forever.
Did I hear?
How did she ask that?
Heart passed.
Yeah, what's the point?
What a load of crap!
If we help them lose our characters,
are you gonna reimburse us for them?
Or is this a trick to weaken the
tribe so you can take over? Hey!
You're wrong.
We're not tricking you.
We know how hard you work
to build your characters up,
and no amount of money
can replace their loss.
We're not asking this lightly.
We're begging you to help us.
Right now,
our friends are fighting the American
players alongside the Underworld,
but they're outnumbered and
they need reinforcements.
You're all SAO survivors, so you
should be tough enough to deal with it!
Screw your sob story!
You think you're all that just
because you were in that game?
Well, here's your chance to
prove how badass you are!
Why should we care about
hijackers or AIs with souls?
Don't bring this real-life crap
into our game and expect us to help!
You and the rest of your
SAO club can deal with it!
Go save the day again, you stuck-up jerks!
It didn't work.
No matter what I say, I don't care.
You're right.
this is a real-life problem
and as for us survivors
yeah some of us do blur the
line between the real world and
the virtual but we don't
think we're tougher or better
than anyone here none of us
think we're heroes me and Silica
she and I go to a special school for
survivors once a month the students
have to go to counseling because of the
trauma we still deal with they ask us
painful questions.
They make some of the kids take
medication, even though it makes them
sick.
And the government?
They're afraid of us, so they
monitor us like we're a bunch
of criminals.
The truth is, it's not just us at the
returnee school they're suspicious
of.
It's all VR MMO players.
They think we're all a bunch of deadbeats.
Losers dragging society
down.
Cowards who don't pay taxes
and can't face reality.
People are saying we need
the draft back to force
us to enlist because at
least we can be useful there.
And even though they think that
about us, you know what I believe?
That this here, this is reality.
This world and all the other
Virtual worlds connected
to it they're real they're
not just games we play here
in VR I have a real life and
I have real friends I laugh
and I cry and I feel real
feelings the same as offline
isn't it like that for you we
pour our hearts and souls into
this world because it's different
from what we got out there but
if it's all just a stupid game
everything we've been through
and felt here is fake if so then
in the end what is real for us
all the worlds we've grown fused together
they're as thick and
tall as the world tree
and from them from them the underworld
started to bloom I want
to protect it so please
Please, please, help us.
Don't stop!
Cut the next one!
We'll see you
next
time.